<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Kurt Fehlhauer</title><link>https://kurtfehlhauer.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Kurt Fehlhauer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 07:03:52 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kurtfehlhauer.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rust's Rocket</title><link>https://kurtfehlhauer.com/posts/rusts-rocket/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 07:03:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kurtfehlhauer.com/posts/rusts-rocket/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://rocket.rs"&gt;Rocket&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://crates.io/crates/rocket"&gt;crate&lt;/a&gt; provides a lot of web server functionality that is simple to use. It compares well to other web-server backend libraries like &lt;a href="https://flask.palletsprojects.com"&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt; in Python. Currently, no Rust framework even registers on the &lt;a href="https://survey.stackoverflow.co/2023/?mod=djemCIO#section-most-popular-technologies-web-frameworks-and-technologies"&gt;Hacker Rank&lt;/a&gt; surveys of favorite web frameworks. That will change. Rocket is easy to use with great documentation and has over 21k stars on GitHub. This is a brief but detailed introduction to using Rocket, by the end of this post you should have a basic understanding of how to get, post, and put using Rocket.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exploring Rust For Data Engineering Part 1</title><link>https://kurtfehlhauer.com/posts/exploring-rust-for-data-engineering-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 08:46:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kurtfehlhauer.com/posts/exploring-rust-for-data-engineering-part-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rust is gaining increasing recognition as the most loved language in the &lt;a href="https://survey.stackoverflow.co/2022#technology-most-loved-dreaded-and-wanted"&gt;Stack Overflow developer surveys&lt;/a&gt;. As such, it&amp;rsquo;s natural to wonder about its potential within the realm of data engineering. Will data engineers begin to love Rust too, or is it just hype? Love versus adoption are two different things as shown by &lt;a href="https://redmonk.com/sogrady/2023/05/16/language-rankings-1-23/"&gt;The RedMonk Programming Language Rankings: January 2023&lt;/a&gt;. Over the coming weeks and months, I aim to explore and share my insights into the possible trajectories for Rust within this domain.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Two Scala Libraries Every Data Engineer Should Know</title><link>https://kurtfehlhauer.com/posts/two-scala-libraries-every-data-engineer-should-know/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 10:01:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://kurtfehlhauer.com/posts/two-scala-libraries-every-data-engineer-should-know/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As data engineers, we deal with a lot of JSON, which is ubiquitous since JSON is easy for developers to add to applications. However, JSON is not an efficient storage format for applications that frequently query or use the data at scale. Unlike Parquet, JSON is not a splittable file format making it less parallelizable in systems like Spark. Often JSON is not performant enough and requires further ETL to be converted to formats like Parquet which is a splittable file format and therefore parallelizable. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to demonstrate how two Scala libraries can work together to convert JSON to Parquet without using Spark, &lt;a href="https://github.com/zio/zio-json"&gt;zio-json&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/mjakubowski84/parquet4s"&gt;Parquet4s&lt;/a&gt;. A working knowledge of functional programming in Scala and Zio is helpful, but not required.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>